For this demonstration, we'll use TTN network server.
But the registration process is very similar if you use another one.
So we go on the TTN console and there I can see two sections, one on the right, the gateway section
and one on the left, the application section.
We'll see soon the application part.
But for the moment we're dealing with gateways.
So on this page here you can see all my registered gateway.
I've got a lot, but only a few are really connected at the moment.
Anyway, I'm going to register a new one.
So I hit the register gateway button and I enter a new page asking me for my gateway EUI.
This is the number we talked about just before, so you just have to enter it here.
I confirm.
Then we need to enter a gateway ID that you can make up.
Be careful because we are only allowed to use lowercase letters.
And finally, we need to specify the frequency plan, depending of the region where the gateway will
be installed.
I'm in Europe, so I will use the 868 megahertz frequency plan.
And for some reason, TTN prefers SF9 for RX2, which is not the default value in the
LoRaWAN specification.
So I follow their recommendations.
I hit the button register gateway, and here we go.
We are done with the gateway registration part.
We can now see it in the gateway section.
And as soon as the gateway will receive a LoRaWAN packet, it will appear in the live data area here.
But remember, all packets received by the Gateway don't necessarily belong to you because your gateway
is able to receive any LoRaWANpacket and only the network server will identify and let them go to the application
server.
So look here, for example, we've received something the frame from a device sending data in the vicinity.
And if we wanted it the network server to be able to identify the specific device, then we need to register
it.
And it is exactly what we're going to do in the next step.